interstatebatteries.com 2019-09-24

# Privacy Policy | Interstate Batteries

### IMPORTANT – PLEASE READ

WELCOME TO THE INTERSTATE BATTERIES® (“IB”) PRIVACY POLICY. WHEN USING IB’S SERVICES, YOU TRUST US WITH YOUR INFORMATION AND AS SUCH THIS POLICY IS MEANT TO HELP YOU UNDERSTAND WHAT TYPE OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT, WHY WE DO SO AND WHAT CAN BE DONE WITH IT. WE ENCOURAGE YOU TO TAKE THE TIME TO READ THIS POLICY CAREFULLY. THE INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE US WITH WILL BE HANDLED ACCORDING TO THE STANDARDS OUTLINED BELOW.

Incorporation into Conditions of Use

This privacy policy (this “ **Policy** ”) is incorporated in, and subject to, the [Conditions of Use](http://www.interstatebatteries.com/m/help/conditions-of-use) (the “ **Conditions of Use** ”) for IB’s website (the “ **Site** ”). Please refer to the Conditions of Use for definitions of words with initial capitals letters that are not otherwise defined in this Policy.

IB reserves the right, in IB’s sole discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Policy at any time. When IB makes any significant updates to this Policy, IB will post a notice in a prominent place on our website for a period of thirty (30) days to make you aware of the changes that have been made. For ease of reference, IB will also indicate when the most recent version of the Policy took effect. By your continued use of the Site, you consent to the revised terms of our Policy. You should read this Policy periodically for changes. If you use the Site after IB posts changes to this Policy, you are deemed to have accepted the changed Policy. 

This Policy was last changed on October 22, 2018.

Information Collection and Submission

IB collects information to provide better services for all of its users. When you visit the Site, you acknowledge that you may be providing IB with two specific types of information: (i) information that you provide which personally identifies you or your business (“ **Personally Identifiable Information** ”) and (ii) information that you provide, or that we collect as you interact with the Site, which does not personally identify you or your business (“ **Site-Use Information** ”). 

_Personally Identifiable Information_. Throughout the Site, you may voluntarily submit Personally Identifiable Information that personally identifies you. For example, the Site may ask you to voluntarily submit Personally Identifiable Information if you register for the Site. Personally Identifiable Information includes, but is not limited to, your (a) name, (b) company’s name, (c) department, (d) physical address, (e) phone number, (f) fax number, (g) e-mail address, and (h) billing information.

_Site-Use Information_. To help IB tailor the Site to the needs and interests of the Site’s visitors, IB may collect various types of Site-Use Information that do not identify you personally. For example, when you visit the Site, IB’s server, through the use of tracking devices, may collect Site-Use Information pertaining to you, including, but not limited to, the length of time you spend on the Site, which pages you visited within the Site, which site you visited before coming to the Site, and which site you accessed when you left the Site.

Cookies

IB uses various technologies to collect and store information when you visit our site, this includes the use of “cookie,” which is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record keeping purposes, or similar technologies to identify your browser or device. IB reserves the right to place these cookies in the browser files of your computer. You can configure your browser to refuse cookies, or to warn you before a cookie is placed. If you disable cookies, some parts of the Site may not function properly or at all.

Do Not Track

At this time sites on the IB Network do not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include ‘do not track’ instructions. However, you can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. You may set your browser to accept all cookies, block certain or all cookies, or require your consent before a cookie is placed in your browser. 

Security

IB works hard to protect its users from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, destruction or disclosure of information we hold. IB uses commercially reasonable administrative, technical, human, and physical measures to protect your information in IB’s possession against loss and theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification. However, IB cannot guarantee that any electronic commerce is totally secure. For example, IB has no control over the information collected by your Internet service provider or your employer (if the Site is made available to you through your employer). Any such third party that collects your information may use the information in accordance with its terms and conditions of use (and related privacy policies), which may be different from this Policy. IB is not responsible for any information collected by such third parties and/or how such information is used or maintained. Neither any third party nor IB has the authority to make any representations or commitments on behalf of the other.

Consent

By using the Site, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to, and processed in, the United States pursuant to this Policy. The Site is hosted in the United States. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, then you may choose that your sole and exclusive remedy is to discontinue using the Site immediately.

Users Outside the United States

Portions of the Site may be hosted on our computer servers in the United States. If you are accessing the Site from outside of the United States, any Personally Identifiable Information collected through the Site may be transferred to the United States or other countries whose privacy laws may be different from those of your home country. Your use of the Site or submission of any Personally Identifiable Information will therefore constitute your consent to the transfer of your Personally Identifiable Information outside of your home country.

**Links To Other Sites**

The Site may contain links to other sites not owned or operated by IB. Those other sites may not have the same privacy policy as IB, and IB is not responsible for the privacy practices, security measures or content of those other sites. When you visit those other sites, you should read their privacy policies. This Policy applies solely to information collected by IB. ****

## Permitted Disclosures

Information about IB’s customers is an important part of its business, and we only share customer information collected on the Site as described below. References to “Information” in this “Permitted Disclosures” section refers to both Personally Identifiable Information and Site Use Information. 

_Affiliates_ : Subsidiaries and affiliates of Interstate Batteries, Inc., and their respective employees, agents, and contractors may access and use your Information in accordance with this Policy. 

_Third-Party Service Providers_ : IB employs other companies and individuals to perform functions on its behalf. Examples include (i) those who help IB manage or provide the Site or process functionality offered by the Site (for example, statistical analyses, data processing, and marketing assistance), and (ii) outside contractors, agents, or sponsors who help IB with the development, administration and maintenance of the Site or process functionality offered by the Site. These outside contractors, agents, or sponsors have access to your Information as needed to perform their functions, and may temporarily store such Information on their servers. 

_Business Transfers_ : As IB continues to develop its business, it may sell or buy stores, subsidiaries, or business units. Therefore, if IB sells all or part of its business or makes a sale or transfer of all or a material part of its assets or equity or is otherwise involved in a merger or transfer of all or a material part of its business, which IB may do at its sole discretion and without requiring your consent, IB may transfer your Information to the party or parties involved in the transaction as part of that transaction.

_Protection of IB and Others_ : Notwithstanding any provision of this Policy to the contrary, IB further reserves the right at all times, and without needing further permission from you to release your Information to: (i) comply with the law regulation, governmental or law enforcement request, or discovery order; (ii) enforce or apply our [Conditions of Use](https://www.amazon.com/gp/browse.html/ref=hp_468496_conditions?node=508088) and other agreements; or (iii) protect the rights, property, or safety of IB, its affiliates, its users, or others. This includes exchanging Information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

_Personally Indefinable Information_ : IB may provide your Personally Identifiable Information to a third party in those instances where you have chosen to receive certain information and have been notified that the fulfilment of such a request requires the sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information.

_With Your Consent_ : Other than as set out in this Policy, you will receive notice when information about you might go to third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information. 

## Use of Information

IB’s use of Personally Identifiable Information and Site Use Information is a necessary part of IB’s business, and IB will use information collected on the Site as described in this Policy. 

_Site Use Information_. In addition to the uses described in the “Permitted Disclosures” section, IB is permitted to use the Site-Use Information in IB’s discretion. Accordingly, IB reserves the right to aggregate Site-Use Information with information collected from other visitors of the Site to track overall visitor traffic patterns, which will allow IB to develop statistics that are helpful to understanding how visitors use the Site. IB may also use Site-Use Information (i) to monitor, maintain, and improve the functionality of the Site, making it more responsive to the needs of the Site’s visitors, and (ii) for historical, statistical, scientific, or other purposes. IB further reserves the right to use, sell, and assign for any and all purposes all Site-Use Information; and you authorize IB to use, sell, and assign, for any and all purposes, all Site-Use Information.

_Personally Identifiable Information_. IB will only use the Personally Identifiable Information you provide us in a manner that is consistent with this Policy. In addition to the other uses described in the “Permitted Disclosures” section, IB may also periodically use your email address to send you promotional materials related to IB’s products and services. If you want to stop receiving such materials from IB, you should follow the unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email. 

_With Your Consent_ : Other than as set out in this Policy, IB will obtain your permission before IB (i) uses your Personally Identifiable Information in a way that is inconsistent with the purpose for which it was submitted, or (ii) shares your Personally Identifiable Information with third parties that are not affiliated with IB.

## To Stop Use of Personally Identifiable Information

If you ask IB in writing to stop using your Personally Identifiable Information, IB will honor that request while retaining any record of your Personally Identifiable Information that is necessary to comply with applicable federal, state, or local law or discovery request.

## Modification of Personally Identifiable Information

We will take commercially reasonable steps to correct any Personally Identifiable Information if you inform us that it is incorrect.

## Data Retention

IB may retain your personal information, including but not limited to your Personally Identifiable Information, as long as necessary to achieve the purpose for which it was collected. This usually will last for the duration of any contractual relationship or as thereafter legally required or permitted by law. 

## California: California Privacy Rights

California law permits customers in California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties and, in some cases, affiliates, for those third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. Under the law, a business must either provide this information or permit California customers to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing.

We may from time to time elect to share certain information about you collected by us on the Service with third parties or affiliates for those third parties’ or affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident, you may opt out of such future sharing of your personal information (as defined by the California Shine the Light Act) and/or request information about our compliance with this law by contacting us at [insert email address]@ibsa.com or by sending a letter to Interstate Batteries, Inc. 12770 Merit Drive, Suite 1000, Dallas, TX 75251, United States (Attention: Legal Counsel). Any such request must include "California Privacy Rights Request" in the first line of the request and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this email address or mail address.   

## Children's Policy

IB does not sell products or services for purchase by children through the Site, nor does it does intend to collect any personal information from children through the Site. Personal information means information that individually identifies an individual including, without limitation, (a) first and last name, (b) physical address, (c) phone number, (d) fax number, (e) e-mail address, and (f) certain types of Site Use Information. Please do not allow children under the age of 13 to provide any personal information via the Site. If you are under the age of 13, you may use the Site only with the involvement of a parent. If IB determines that a child under 13 has provided personal information, IB will delete that personal information as soon as practicable. If you become aware that a child under 13 has provided personal information, please contact IB at the following addresses: Interstate Batteries, 12770 Merit Drive, Dallas, Texas, 75251, Attention: Ecommerce Customer Service; Email: CustomerService@InterstateBatteries.com.

## Questions

If you would like to communicate with us about this Policy or IB’s collection and/or use of your Personally Identifiable Information, please contact IB at the following addresses:

Interstate Batteries, 12770 Merit Drive, Dallas, Texas, 75251, Attention: Customer Service Email: [Contactcenter@ibsa.com](mailto:Contactcenter@ibsa.com).
